

# ROHAAN KHAN

Business Developer | Sales Growth | Performance Marketer | Freelancing Expert

## **ABOUT ME**

I am Rohaan Khan, I am an experienced |4+Years| business developer / Growth Strategist with a track record of driving revenue growth and expanding market share for multiple organizations through various marketing strategies. I specialize in Sales Growth for Startups to Corporate Clients through Freelancing, LinkedIn, Digital Marketing (SMM, SEO). My experience in the industry has given me a deep understanding of different sectors and business models, including B2B, B2C, and SaaS.

## CAREER VISION

My career vision is to leverage my skills, experience, and passion for sales and business growth to make a significant impact on the organizations I work with.

## **SPECIALIZATIONS**

- + Business Development
- + Social Media Marketing
- + Lead Generation
- + Meeting Sales Targets
- + Lead Maturing
- + Customer Support
- + Business Intelligence+ Digital Marketing Strategy
- + Digital Marketing Strategy
- + Customer and Clients Relations
- + Software Project Management
- + CRM's

## GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

Home: +92 302 7702343 Email: rohaan.naeem@gmail.com Islamabad | L

## **EDUCATION**

## NFC INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY, MULTAN Bachelors in Computer Science

2015-2019

Courses included both Computer Science related (programming, databases, data structures, computer modeling and simulations, digital signals, machine learning, network security, artificial intelligence, digital image processing, mobile app development and hardware related courses)

## LAHORE UNIVERSITY OF MANAGEMENT SCIENCES (LUMS), LAHORE Digital Marketing 101 (2023-2023)

Courseline included Marketing Strategies, Facebook Ads, Google Ads, TikTok Ads and LinkedIn Advertisements.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### LEAD BUSINESS DEVELOPER

TripleK Technologies July 2023 - Present | Hybrid | Lahore

- Within a few months, Re-developed firm's business development strategy
- Worked with tools like Apollo, Instantly to map out LikendIn | Email Marketing
- Gathered 3-4 Clients a month to give them a stable revenue.
- Done Project Management for some full stack development projects.
- Took care of 15-20 client closings, from the introductory call to closing the client.

## SR. BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Protovoid Technologies June 2022 - July 2023 (13 Months) | Hybrid | Islamabad

- Lead a team and map out strategies for identifying and prospecting new clients
- Brought business related to WEB Development | Mobile App Development
- Groomed companies freelancing accounts from ZERO to TOP RATED Plus
- Handled 1/1 Meetings with clients, Closed Deals, and tracked performance.
- Met monthly targets on a consistent basis.
- Prepared structured proposals
- Used respective CRMs to build sales pipeline

#### **BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER**

Sectem Technologies June 2021 - May 2022 (1 Year) | On-Site | Islamabad

- Consistently exceeded monthly targets of generating qualified leads and opportunities working to be a consistent top performer
- Closed Deals related to Digital Marketing | WEB and APP Development
- Implemented Marketing strategies
- Groomed companies freelancing accounts from ZERO to TOP RATED
- Used CRMs like Salesforce/ZohoCRM to build a Sales Pipeline

## TOOLS

- Salesforce
- Zapier
- Apollo
- Instantly
- Closely
- ASANA
- HubSpot
- Trello
- Linkedin Sales Navigator
- Upwork/Fiverr/Freelancer
- Facebook Pixel

## SKILLS

- Strong communication
- Meeting KPIs
- Project Management
- Paid Advertisements
- Social Media Marketing
- Leads Maturing
- Project Organization
- Task Management
- Sales Pipelines
- Risk Management
- Agile Methodologies

## OTHER INTERESTS

Apart from being a Business Developer, I have keen interest in Entrepreneurship: I take up interest in starting my own business or working with startups to help them grow.

## SOCIAL MEDIA:



@ROHAANKHAN7



<u>@ROHAANKHAN7</u>

## REFERENCES

References can be summoned upon demand.

#### **BUSINESS DEVELOPER**

## Developers Hub (Pvt). Ltd May 2020 - May 2021 (13 Months) | On-Site | Islamabad

- Worked in a team environment with a team of multiple business developers
- Upscaled business related to Wordpress | SEO | Shopify | Full Stack | Plugin Development | Digital Marketing
- Worked on multiple Upwork accounts (Top Rated Plus)
- Worked closely with the client for requirement gathering and analysis.
- Performed QA before delivering projects to the clients.

#### **BUSINESS DEVELOPER**

#### Open Office Aug 2019 - Apr 2020 (9 Months) | Remote | Islamabad

- Took an Al-based startup towards growth
- Generated \$25k+ revenue within a year (working with a team of BD's)
- Learned about LinkedIn Sales Navigator, SEM, SEO

#### FREELANCER | PROJECT MANAGEMENT

## Upwork, Jan 2020 - Present | Remote

- 3+ years of Experience as an Upwork Freelancer
- \$50k+ in revenue from Upwork
- Groomed Several Employer's accounts from Zero to Top Rated/Top Rated Plus
- Generated revenue for services like Web Development, Mobile App Development, Artificial Intelligence and Digital Marketing

#### FREELANCER | PROJECT MANAGEMENT

#### Fiverr. Oct 2019 - Present | Remote

- 3.5+ years of Experience as an Upwork Freelancer
- \$40k+ in revenue from Upwork
- Groomed Several Employer accounts from Zero to Level Two/Top Rated Plus
- Generated revenue for services like Web Development, Mobile App Development, Artificial Intelligence and Cloud Computing

## LEAD GENERATION INTERN

Syntax Software house May 2019 - July 2019 | On-Site | Bahawalpur

Worked as a Lead Generation Intern at Syntax Software House and learned about identifying, attracting, and nurturing potential customers for businesses.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **UDEMY**

**Business Development for Startup and Tech companies Issued Aug 2021** 

#### **EDUREKA**

Digital marketing

## **HUBSPOT**

Sales Management
Issued Dec 2021

## EROZGAAR

ERozgaar Creative Design Issued May 2019

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Outstaffing deals for organizations that are giving them revenue to date.
- Successfully closing large deals with key clients or partners, resulting in significant revenue growth for the organization.
- Mentoring and coaching junior team members to help them grow and develop in their careers.
- Building strong relationships with clients and partners, leading to repeat business and referrals.
- Building and managing a strong pipeline of leads and opportunities, resulting in consistent sales growth over time.